# Devansh Shah

## Computer Science Engineer

Recent graduate with a major in Computer Science and minor in Finance. Experienced in web and app development. Also, possess enough hands-on with UI/UX development and have an adequate amount of ordeal in marketing and design-related activities.



shahdevansh0111@gmail.com

+971 566687215/+91 9537744544

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

devanshmadd.github.io

linkedin.com/in/devanshshahh in

github.com/devanshmadd

### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Engineering BITS Pilani**

08/2017 - 08/2021

Dubai

Subjects

• Major - Computer Science

Minor - Finance

8 30 CGPA

# Senior Secondary and Secondary

**Udgam School** 

04/2011 - 05/2017 Ahmedabad, India

Performance

• 87% class 12 10 CGPA in class 10

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Technical Executive Intern**

Galaxkey Ltd.

01/2021 - 07 / 2021 Dubai, UAE

Platform that provides data security and cyber security solutions. Visit Galaxkey.

- Developed a full-stack web portal to track the deals and simplify the deal tracking process which helped them reduce 90% of the communication gap and streamline
- Al Algorithm to help sort the files into their categories and further encrypt them and avoid important data leak/breach.
- Looked after the daily operations, which also involved marketing activities.

## Co-Founder, CTO SolarGridX

12/2019 - 01/2021

Duhai & India

SolarGridX is a crowd-investing platform where people can Buy-Sell "fractional" digital ownership of solar panels. Visit SolarGridX.

- Developed the beta iOS and web application which were used as the prototypes for the pitch with investors across different venture capitalists.
- Won multiple Hackathons and Accelerators.

# **Developer Intern**

State Bank of India 06/2019 - 08/2019

Mumbai

Yono Development - IT Sector of SBI

### Achievements/Tasks

• Reduced the physical workload by developing a web application that helps the employees and the department heads to track the status of the ongoing projects and update the daily tasks easily.

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

Microsoft Imagine Cup World Finalist 2021 - Team Tandemly (02/2021 - 03/2021)

Made it through to the top 12 teams of the Microsoft Imagine cup 2021. Tandemly - Team details -Microsoft Imagine Cup

Apple Worldwide Developers Conference Scholarship Holder (05/2019 - 06/2019)

Got selected among the top 350 scholars worldwide to attend the WWDC 2019 event live. WWDC Scholars

# **SKILLS**

Computer languages: C++, Java, Swift, Python, PHP, HTML 5, CSS, MySQL, ReactJS



Design/editing Software's: Adobe Photoshop, Figma Lightroom, Illustrator, iMovie, FCP, Sketch (UI/UX)











MS Office applications.











# PERSONAL PROJECTS

iOS Application for BITS Sports Festival -Biggest inter-university sports fest. - App Store Published - Helped in marketing and sponsorship of the whole event

Covid-19 Dashboard with live news and statistical data using Highcharts and NewsAPI

Designed an iOS app for monitoring a person's healthy routine and provide suggestions based on BMÍ.

Study project - involving Nature Inspired Computing using BAT Algorithm and another involving Delay Differential Equations and its applications.

Developed multiple games like Tic tac toe, Hue Puzzle etc. using Swift Playgrounds

# **ORGANISATIONS**

President and Head of Entrepreneurship at CIIED (08/2019 - 07 / 2021)

Lead the entrepreneurship and incubation activities by bringing in multiple sponsors and organisation at the university events

Technical manager at ACM(Association for computing machinery) (08/2020 - 07 / 2021) Lead the technical activities and bootcamps at the university.

Core Committee member at the IEI(Institute of Engineer's, India) (08/2018 - 07 / 2021)

### **LANGUAGES**

English, Hindi and Gujarati Full Professional Proficiency

### **INTERESTS**

Photography & Videography

Football

Cricket